<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Hanoi Historic Sites</string>

    <string name="button_directions">Get Directions</string>
    <string name="button_youtube">Watch YouTube Video</string>
    <string name="button_back">Back</string>
    <string name="language_switch">Tiếng Việt</string>

    <string name="van_mieu_title">Temple of Literature</string>
    <string name="van_mieu_summary">The Temple of Literature was built in 1070 under King Ly Thanh Tong, initially as a temple dedicated to Confucius, sages, and scholars, as well as a place of study for the crown princes. In 1076, King Ly Nhan Tong established the Imperial Academy next to it, originally exclusive to the royal family and aristocrats. In 1253, King Tran Thai Tong transformed the Imperial Academy into the National College, opening its doors to talented commoners. This complex is not just a school but also a symbol of Vietnam\'s cultural heritage and tradition of learning. Its most prominent feature is the 82 stone turtle steles, honoring the names of 1307 doctors who passed 82 examinations from 1442 to 1779. These steles are a precious documentary heritage, reflecting the educational philosophy of feudal dynasties. Through history\'s ups and downs, the Temple of Literature has retained its ancient charm and remains an unmissable destination, symbolizing the intellect and culture of Vietnam.</string>

    <string name="ho_guom_title">Hoan Kiem Lake and Ngoc Son Temple</string>
    <string name="ho_guom_summary">Hoan Kiem Lake, also known as Sword Lake, is the historical and spiritual heart of Hanoi. Its name is tied to the heroic legend of King Le Loi (15th century). According to legend, during the war against the Ming invaders, the king was lent a magical sword by the Golden Turtle God. After peace was restored, while boating on the lake, the Golden Turtle surfaced to reclaim the sword, which the king returned. The lake was then renamed Hoan Kiem (Lake of the Returned Sword). Located on Jade Island in the northern part of the lake, Ngoc Son Temple is an architectural marvel in harmony with nature. Initially built to worship Buddha, it was later renovated to honor the national hero Tran Hung Dao and Van Xuong De Quan, the deity of literature and examinations. The entrance is marked by the The Huc Bridge (Bridge of the Rising Sun), painted in vermilion red, along with the Pen Tower and Ink Slab, creating a timeless architectural ensemble rich in cultural significance, symbolizing the martial spirit and scholarly tradition of the Hanoian people.</string>

    <string name="hoang_thanh_title">Imperial Citadel of Thang Long</string>
    <string name="hoang_thanh_summary">The Imperial Citadel of Thang Long, a UNESCO World Heritage Site, is a historical chronicle written in architecture and artifacts spanning 13 centuries. It served as the capital of Vietnam under the Ly, Tran, Le So, and Mac dynasties. The heart of the Citadel is the area of the ancient Hanoi fortress, where archaeologists have discovered layers of architectural ruins and artifacts stacked upon one another. Excavations from 2002-2004 at 18 Hoang Dieu Street unearthed a priceless complex of relics, testifying to the continuous existence and development of the Thang Long capital. Prominent remaining structures include the Doan Mon gate (main entrance to the Forbidden City), the foundation of Kinh Thien Palace with its majestic stone dragons, the Hau Lau (Princess\'s Pavilion), and the Hanoi Flag Tower. The Citadel was not only the political center but also the cultural and economic hub of the country for a long period, reflecting the unique urban planning and architectural artistry of ancient Vietnamese people.</string>

    <string name="lang_bac_title">Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum</string>
    <string name="lang_bac_summary">After President Ho Chi Minh passed away in 1969, following the wishes of the entire Party and people, the Politburo decided to preserve his body for the long term and construct a mausoleum in the historic Ba Dinh Square. This is the very place where he read the Declaration of Independence, giving birth to the Democratic Republic of Vietnam on September 2, 1945. The project began on September 2, 1973, with the assistance of Soviet experts in embalming techniques, but the architectural design was entirely Vietnamese. The Mausoleum\'s architecture combines modern and traditional elements, reminiscent of a stylized lotus flower. Building materials were gathered from all corners of the country, symbolizing the unity and heartfelt devotion of the Vietnamese people to Uncle Ho. The Mausoleum is a monument of immense political and cultural significance, a place for Vietnamese people and international friends to pay their respects to the great national leader.</string>

    <string name="nha_tu_hoa_lo_title">Hoa Lo Prison Relic</string>
    <string name="nha_tu_hoa_lo_summary">Hoa Lo Prison was built by French colonialists in 1896 in central Hanoi to imprison and torture Vietnamese revolutionaries and patriots. With its high stone walls, dense barbed wire, brutal cells, and a guillotine, it was known as a \"hell on earth,\" a testament to the crimes of the colonial regime and the indomitable spirit of the Vietnamese people. Many revolutionary leaders of Vietnam were once imprisoned here. During the Vietnam War, the prison was used to hold American pilots shot down over North Vietnam, who sarcastically nicknamed it the \"Hanoi Hilton.\" Today, only a small part of the prison remains, but it is enough to recount two important historical periods, displaying artifacts and images that denounce war crimes and celebrate the patriotism and sacrifice of past generations.</string>

    <string name="chua_mot_cot_title">One Pillar Pagoda</string>
    <string name="chua_mot_cot_summary">The One Pillar Pagoda, also known as Dien Huu Tu (meaning \"long-lasting happiness\"), has its origins in a dream of King Ly Thai Tong (1028-1054). The king dreamt that the Bodhisattva Avalokiteshvara, seated on a lotus throne, extended a hand to lead him up. Upon waking, the king recounted the dream to his court, and the monk Thien Tue advised him to build a pagoda on a single stone pillar in the middle of a pond, creating a lotus throne for the Buddha as in his dream. The pagoda was built in 1049 with a unique architecture: a square shrine placed on a single stone pillar, rising from a square lotus pond. The entire structure evokes the image of a pure lotus flower emerging from the muddy water, a noble symbol in Buddhism. In 1954, before withdrawing from Hanoi, French forces mined and destroyed the pagoda. It was later rebuilt to its original design and has become one of the most distinctive cultural symbols of the capital city.</string>

    <string name="chua_tran_quoc_title">Tran Quoc Pagoda</string>
    <string name="chua_tran_quoc_summary">Tran Quoc Pagoda is considered the oldest pagoda in Hanoi, with a history dating back to the 6th century, during the reign of King Ly Nam De (544-548). Initially named Khai Quoc, it was built on the banks of the Red River. In the 17th century, due to riverbank erosion, the pagoda was moved to its current location on a small island on the eastern side of West Lake. The name Tran Quoc (meaning \"defending the country\") was given during the reign of King Le Hy Tong. The pagoda\'s architecture is a harmonious blend of solemnity, ancient beauty, and the poetic scenery of West Lake. Its highlight is the 11-story hexagonal stupa, 15 meters high, with each level featuring six arched doorways, inside of which sits a statue of Amitabha Buddha made of precious stone. Over thousands of years of history, Tran Quoc Pagoda has not only been an important Buddhist center but also a famous scenic spot, attracting numerous tourists and Buddhists for pilgrimage and sightseeing.</string>

    <string name="nha_hat_lon_title">Hanoi Opera House</string>
    <string name="nha_hat_lon_summary">The Hanoi Opera House is a magnificent architectural work, built by the French colonial government from 1901 to 1911. The design, modeled after the Opéra Garnier in Paris, is in the neoclassical style but on a smaller scale and using materials suited to the local climate. It was not only a center for classical performing arts for the French elite and wealthy Vietnamese of the time but also a witness to many significant historical events. Notably, the square in front of the Opera House was the site of a major rally on August 19, 1945, which kicked off the General Uprising to seize power in Hanoi. Today, the Opera House serves as a national stage for concerts, opera, ballet, and major cultural events, standing as an architectural and cultural icon of the capital.</string>

    <string name="bao_tang_dth_title">Vietnam Museum of Ethnology</string>
    <string name="bao_tang_dth_summary">Established in 1995 and inaugurated in 1997, the Vietnam Museum of Ethnology is a leading center for cultural research and exhibition, focusing on the 54 ethnic groups of Vietnam. The museum\'s mission is to preserve, study, and present the rich and diverse cultural heritage of these groups. It features three main exhibition areas. The two-story Trong Dong building houses the permanent exhibition, showcasing costumes, work tools, musical instruments, beliefs, and customs of each ethnic group. The outdoor exhibition (Architectural Garden) is a major attraction, featuring life-sized replicas of traditional houses from various ethnic groups, such as the Bahnar communal house, the Ede longhouse, and the Hani earthen house. The Canh Dieu building is dedicated to exhibitions on Southeast Asian cultures, fostering cultural connections within the region.</string>

    <string name="den_quan_thanh_title">Quan Thanh Temple</string>
    <string name="den_quan_thanh_summary">Quan Thanh Temple, also known as Tran Vu Quan, is one of the \"Four Sacred Temples\" that guarded the four cardinal directions of the ancient Thang Long citadel, specifically protecting the north. The temple was built very early, during the reign of King Ly Thai To (1010-1028), to worship Huyen Thien Tran Vu, a Taoist deity who governed the north and helped protect the people from evil spirits and monsters. The most remarkable and valuable feature of the temple is the bronze statue of Huyen Thien Tran Vu, cast in 1677. Standing 3.96 meters tall and weighing about 4 tons, it is a masterpiece of 17th-century Vietnamese bronze casting. The statue depicts the deity in a majestic seated posture, his left hand forming a mudra and his right hand holding a sword entwined with a snake, resting on the back of a turtle, symbolizing power and the suppression of evil. Quan Thanh Temple is not only an important historical and religious site but also a cultural space deeply imbued with the artistic marks of ancient sculpture and architecture.</string>

</resources>